Mss.326.F33
American Philosophical Society
Sol Feinstone Slavery collection, 1773-1888
Mss.326.F33
American Philosophical Society
0.5 Linear feet 85 items
This collection of documents includes letters, broadsides, bills of sale, deeds of purchase, and wills, relating to various slaves. There are also documents from notable Americans concerning the slave question, such as John Brown, Frederick Douglass, William Lloyd Garrison, and Andrew Jackson.
85 items.
Feinstone, Sol,1888-1980,collector.
Box 1
Existence and Location of Originals note
Originals in David Library of the American Revolution, Washington Crossing, Pa.
Immediate Source of Acquisition note
Received from Sol Feinstone and accessioned, 07/01/1969 (1063ms).
African American History Note
A rich source of material for students of African American history.
Early American History Note
The Feinstone Slavery Collection complements the much larger Sol Feinstone Collection of American Revolution. This smaller collection (one box) contains documents pertaining to slavery in the early republic. There are records of sale and emancipation along with some correspondence and other miscellaneous materials. Much of the material is from Virginia.
Brown, John, 1800-1859; Douglass, Frederick, 1818-1895; Garrison, William Lloyd, 1805-1879; Jackson, Andrew, 1767-1845; Abolition, emancipation, freedom; African American; African Americans--History--To 1863; Early National Politics; Legal Records; Miscellaneous; Official Government Documents and Records; Pennsylvania History; Reconstruction; Slavery -- United States.; Slaves, slavery, slave trade
- Series I. Original documents
  Scope and Contents note
  This series consists of original documents relating to slavery, including correspondence, bills of sale, and emancipation papers.
  - Item 1
  - Item 2
- Beale, John Bill of sale to Sam Henry, 1792 Sept 3
- Booth, William Deed to Richard H. Lee, 1773 Dec 3
- Bucklin, Joseph Grant of Freedom, 1782 Sept 21
- Butler, Christopher Deed, bill of sale negro woman to William A Washington, 1792 Aug 30
- Campbell, Archibald General Instructions for the Jamaica Rangers, 1782 Oct 1
- Donaldson, Alexander and Robert Jeffries, 1752 Oct 7
- Fonblanque, John Legal case and opinion, 1792 Jan 14
- Hufty, Mary Bill of sale of negro to Adam Stricker, 1783 Feb 22
- Irwin, Thomas to Samuel Massey, 1777 May
- Moore, John Bill of sale of negro child to her mother, 1799 Nov 30
- Philippe, Charles to Monsieur Dandas, 1799 June 10
- Powell, Leven - Deed of Emancipation, 1790 Nov 20
- Slave collar - tag only, 1790?
- Smith, C to Evert Bancker, 1780 July 13
- Tole, Richard - Statement that William is free, 1770 Jan 17
- Troup, John to Evert Bancker, 1769 Sept 7
- Troup, John to Evert Bancker, 1769 Oct 21
- Walker, Baylor Certification of sale of negro woman to Henry Brown, 1764 Nov 23
- Williamson, Adam Order to Baron, 1795 Jan 31
- Series II. Photocopied documents (Box 2)
  This series consists of photocopied documents relating to slavery, including correspondence. Of particular note is correspondence from John Brown to his family.
  - Item 1
- Affidavit in re last will of Pienoel, 1838 August 7
- African Squadron Unparallelled Success - Broadside, 1842?
- Baldey, George to Commanding officer of troops detached to Brasher City, 1868 October 19
- Baldey, George - Order to Capt William Sterling - telegraph notes, 1868 October 22
- Baldey, George to Capt William Sterling, 1868 October 31
- Banque des Citoyens de la Louisiane - appraisal of Lizardi Plantation, 1834 December
- Beale, John Bill of sale to Sam Henry - slaves, 1792 Sept 3
- Booth, William Deed to Richard H Lee, slaves, 1773 Dec 3
- Brown, John photograph, 1856
- Brown, John to "Dear wife and children, everyone", 1856 March 6
- Brown, John? to "My dear wife and children" Frederick Douglas to 'My dear friends", 1858 Jan 30
- Brown, John to H N Rust, 1857 April 16
- Brown, John, Jr to Francis Jackson Garrison, 1883 March 27
- Brown, Owen to Grandaughter Ruth, 1851 Feb 16
- Bucklin, Joseph Grant of freedom to Piony and Sylvia, 1782 Sept 21
- Butler, Christopher Deed - bill of sale negro woman to William A Washington, 1792 August 30
- Cameron, Charles to George Harrison, 1814 Oct 11
- Campbell, A Affidafit of William Prant, negro, 1853 Jan 20
- Campbell, Archibald General instructions for the Jamaica Rangers, 1782 Oct 1
- Carson, Thomas Legal judgment, Daniel Johnston vs Wilson Carman and judjment on negro woman, 1811 April 17
- Cornish, Henry Bill of sale to Jonathan Elmer, 1814 March 5
- Craig, James to William Meredith, 1813 May 29
- Craig, James to William Meredith, 1813 June 19
- Crowson, Thomas Bill of sale for negro boy to John H Bryan, 1834 October 17
- A Defence of the South by Rev Iveson Brookes, 1850
- A Defence of Southern Slavery by a southern clergy, 1851
- Donaldson, Alexander and Robert Jeffries disposition on condition of slave ship, 1752 October 7
- Douglas, Frederick to Mrs Parker, ? April 5
- Douglas, Frederick to Robert Adams, 1888 Dec 4
- Eanes, Thomas and William Cain Bond to Henrietta R Robertson, 1840 Jan 1
- Farmer Satirical poem, Philadelphia, 1807
- Fonblanque, John Legal case and opinion bonds in will of W A Wright, 1792 Jan 14
- Foster, John G to Admiral, 1864 Nov 24
- Garrison, William Lloyd to L A Miller, 1832 August 18
- Le Genealogiste Ameriquain, 1789?
- Gurney, John and E G Ponder Receipt for purchase of negro to Joel may, 1846 Dec 1
- Hamilton, A W, George Hamilton, James Hamilton Division of slaves, 1854 Sept 27
- Hatch, J H to Major Ord, 1868 Oct 27
- Hayne, Robert to Hon L D Miller, 1832 Dec 12
- Hickman D H, Arch Young, John L Hickman, J H Hickman Receipt for sale of slaves to Thaddeus B Hickman, 1859 March 15
- Hudson, J B to Editor, "Democrat and Freedom", 1848 Jan 20
- Hufty, Mary Bill of sale of negro to Adam Stricker, 1783 Feb 22
- Hugo, Victor Letter on John Brown, 1860
- Hunter, Robert M T to J N Tarnack, G B Cooke, and J Capson, 1844 Aug 14
- Irwin, Thomas to Samuel Massey, 1777 May
- Jackson, Andrew to Major Gardener, 1834 Nov 8
- James, Spencer Bill of sale to William Bourn, 1843 march 20
- Jervis, John Bounty claim for William Lewis, negro, 1865 Aug 14
- Kirby, Fayette F. Bill of sale of three negro females to Benjamin N Watson, 1842 May 25
- Lamme, Samuel Grant of freedom to negro woman, Sarah, 1815 June 12
- Kirtly, Francis Bill of sale for six slaves to William Buford, 1814 March 21
- Keen, Francis I, Bill of sale to Margaret G Flournay, 1840
- Kay, John Bill of sale to Lucy Gatewood, 1802 Nov 30
- Lincoln, Abraham to Gen Meiggs, 1862 Nov 7
  Forgery cf: Washington, Geo to Jacob? Tyler", (forgery by Joseph Cosey)
- Lincoln, Abraham, to the Secretary of War Stanton, 1862 June 5, 1865 March 16
  Forgery cf: Washington, George to Jacob? Tyler. (Forgery by Joseph Cosey)
- Lundy, Benjamin to Thomas Gregg and Genius of Universal Emancipation broadside, 1838 April 15
- Macaulay, G. Receipt on account of expenses of catured negroes, 1813 January 26
- Maryland concerning death of volunteer Alred B Hilton - broadside, 1864
- McClees, James by Charles McClees - Receipt for one negro slave, Grace, 1858 Aug 21
- McKim, J M to A Boyd. Also page from John Brown's book, 1866 July 30
- Manifest of negroes on the brig Uncas - broadside, 1839 Nov 19
- Minutes of proceedings of convention of delegates from abolition socieities, 1794 Jan 1
- Moore, John - Bill of sale of negro child to her mother, 1799 Nov 30
- Pennsylvania Society for Pormoting the Abolition of Slavery Constitution, 1787
- Percy, Felix, N.P. Bill of sale of negro, 1847 Feb 27
- Philippe, Charles to Monsieur Dundas, 1799 June 10
- Phillippo, J. W. to "My Dear Sir". Also Interesting Case of a Slave Girl, 1829, 1857 Oct 5
- Phillipo, James to John Williams, 1841 June 4
- Phillips, Wendell - Quote from Lafayette, 1864 May
- Powell, Leven - Deed of emancipation, 1790 Nov 20
- Preston, William C. to "Dear Sir", 1828 September
- Public sale of negroes - broadside, 1833 March 5
- Radical members of the South Carolina legislature - photograph, 1866?
- Rules and regulations concerning commercial intercourse - printed, 1864 July 29
- Rutan, Paul and John F Post - Bill of sale to Peter Jackson, 1815 April 22
- Sacket, Augustus to Evert Bancker, 1810 March 26
- Scott, Winfield to Col W J Worth, 1831 September 19
- Sewell, L. to Gen Robert C Buchannan, 1868 October 29
- Sewell, L. to Capt William Sterling, 1868 October 30
- Sewell, L to Capt William Sterling, 1868 October 31
- A Short Catechism on Negro Equality - broadside, 1836?
- Slave collar tag describing collar, 1790?
- Smith, C to Evert Bancker, 1780 July 13
- Smith, F O - Bill of sale to William Stone, 1844 Jan 2
- South Carolina - Settlement of William Harth Estate, 1847 January 15
- Stone, J M to Gov George R Gilmer of Georjia, 1830 January 8
- Thurston, David to Rev William Jenks, 1812 April 15
- Tole, Richard - Statement that William is free, 1770 January 17
- Troup, John to Evert Bancker, 1769 October 21
- Troup, John to Evert Bancker, 1769 September 7
- Walker, Baylor - Certification of sale of negro woman to Henry Brown, 1764 Nov 23
- Williamson, Adam - Order to Baron de la Valtiere and receipt, 1795 January 31
- Yates, William - Bill of sale for negro man to Peter T Heckin, 1838 October 12